Guide to the Alison Jolly papers, circa 1919-2014
Jolly, Alison papers
- Series III. Notes and Papers
  - General Documents
    - letter to RJ Author: AJ Ambaro and Berenty, 1996; handwritten letter (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - interview with Pierre Ramahatra Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 2000; handwritten interview transcription (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Rencontre avec L'Androy Author: Georges Heurtebize Location:, typed account (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - notes on travel with Georges Heurtebize, George and Joanna Macdonald Author: Alison Jolly Location: Ambaro, 1996; typed notes (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Rites Funeraires Tandroy, Kokolampo: Possession Author: Philibert Tsimamandro University of Tulear, 1998; typed summary of thesis (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - independence of Madagascar, 1946 Author: Jacques and Raymond Rabemananjara Location: Neuilly, France, 1946; typed document (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - interviews with Jean de Heaulme Author: Alison Jolly Location: Fort Dauphin, 1998-2000; handwritten and typed notes (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Rehomahas notebook of names Location: Berenty, 1930s; typed list (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - interview notes Author: AJ Berenty, 1998-2000; typed notes (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - tourist interviews Author: Alison Jolly, 2000; typed notes (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - July-Oct Diary Author: AJ Lewes and Sark, 1999; diary notebook (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - interview Chantal and Georges du Pray Author: Alison Jolly Location: Sainte foy la grande, 1999; typed and handwritten notes, photo and guide (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - interview Guy and Eliane Marcou Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lamonzie St. Martin France, 2000; handwritten letters and photos (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - interview Maitre Christophie Author: Alison Jolly Fort Dauphin, 2003; notebook and letters (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - letters between Duke students, 1970s; handwritten letters (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Madagascar Matin, 1972; photocopied news article (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Aina R'Abel Author: AJ Berenty, 1990s; handwritten notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Madagascar Mica mining, photocopied news article (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - La Carte Imperiale Author: Maurice Martin du Gard, 1940-45; photocopied chapter (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Brochure of Arambelo Author: Georges Heurtebize Location: Berenty, brochure (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - de Heaulme photo Author: Sheila O'Connor Berenty, 1985; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - de Heaulme photo, 1990s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - La Basse Terre Location: Reunion, C19th?; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Henry de Heaulme Location: Analabe, 1960s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Micocebus griseorufus Location: Berenty, photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Henry and Marcelle de Heaulme with Jean Location: 1st House, Fort Dauphin, 1920s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Alain de Heaulme boy scout trip Location: Tana, 1920s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Alain de Heaulme, uncle Villentroy, Henry de Heaulme, 1919?; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Alain de Heaulme boy scout troop Location: Tana, 1920s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Quentin de Heaulme Location: Berenty, 2005; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - de Heaulme new house Location: Fort Dauphin, 1930s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - family photo Location: Fort Dauphin, 1940s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Rene Zingo and Jean de Heaulme with trans-Africa Land rover Location: Fort Dauphin, 1950s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Henry de Heaulme and Bernard Astraud Location: Rhodesia, 1950s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Bernard Astraud in cockpit Location: Rhodesia, 1950s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Jacques de Heaulme teaches Lahivano to ride Location: Berenty, 1960s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Berenty gate Location: Berenty, 1960; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Jean de Heaulme portrait Location: Fort Dauphin, 1965; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Marcelle de Heaulme portrait Location: Fort Dauphin, 1960s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chantal de Heaulme treats scalded toddler Location: Berenty, 1960s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chantal de Heaulme with newborn Tandroy Location: Berenty, 1960s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Rekanoky cutting sisal Location: Berenty, 1980s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Jean de Heaulme, Nicolas Hulot, Helen Crowley Location: Berenty, 1993; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Henry de Heaulme portrait Location: Berenty, 1960s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Jean de Heaulme pilot Location: Berenty, 1990s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - sorting sisal Author: Guy Marcou, 1950s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Henry de Heaulme, Uncle Villentroy, Alain de Heaulme Location: Tana, 1999; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chantal de Heaulme, Georges Dupray wedding Location: Berenty, 1963; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chantal de Heaulme, Georges Dupray wedding Location: Berenty, 1963; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Thorianite mine at Betanimena Author: Alison Jolly Betanimena, 1963; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Thorianite mine at Betanimena Author: Alison Jolly Betanimena, 1963; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "The Appel" Author: Guy Marcou, 1950s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - sawing planks Location: Analabe forest, 1960s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - selection of tourist photos of Madagascar Location: Madagascar, photographs (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Images de la famille de heaulem, typed list (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Madagascar documents Location: Madagascar, 1980s?; manual, letters and articles (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
    - Evolution of Primate Behaviour 2nd edition, permissions, 1983-4; letters (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
      David Attenborough, T.R. Anthony, Altmann, Irwin Bernstein, Mireille Bertrand, Nick Bluton-Jones, Richard Andrew, F. Bourliere, Jerome Bruner, John Beuttner-Janusch, Julia Chase, Chevalier-Skolnikoffs, Crockett, Coimbra-Filho, David Chivers, John Crook, Roger T. Davis, John Deag, R.O. Dodsworth, Dohl, Gerald Doyle, Frank du Mond, Eisenberg, A. Dixson, W. Dittus, N. DeVore,W. Fitzgerald, Dian Fossey, Flegle, R. Fontaine, Froelich, H.J. Fletcher, Marcel Hladik, C. Harcourt, C. Georgi, K. Glander, J. Goodall, Beatrice Gardner, A. Gautier, T. Grand, Fay Hall, H. F. Hausfater, Hess-Haeser, van Hoof, Barbara Harrison, Tony Jacklin, J.H. Kaufmann, A. Kortlandt, Hans Kummer, S. Karger, G.E. Hutchinson, Adrian Kortlandt, E.H. Lenneberg, Lawick-Goodall, E.D. Lacey, Malenky, P. Marler, David McNeill, B.M. Marriott, Desmond Morris, John Napier, National Geographic, D. Olsen, Paul Parey, Patterson, S. Peet, J.J. Petter, Jean Piaget, B. Rensch, P. Rodman, Jim Rawson, M. Rose, Suzanne Ripley, Michael Rose, L. Rosenblum, Hugh and Thelma Rowell, San Diego zoo, Doris Sorby, B. Spock, S. Strum, Ian Tattersall, H.S. Terrace, J. Teas, S. Uehara, A.H. Walker, S.L. Williams, Frans de Waal, A. Whitten, R. Wrangham, R. Zimmerman,
    - Original photographs, Evolution of Primate Behaviour 2nd edition, 1980s; photos and letters (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Coffey, Charles Jamsen, van Lewick, Ed Lacey, S.L. Williams, R. Zimmerman, Bellugi, Pollock, Marler, R.D. Martin, D. Sorby, D. Symons, Patterson, Koko, Mirror
    - Duplicates of articles and notes Location: Madagascar, notes and articles (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Baby doom - a history of infant feeding' Author: Alison Jolly and RJ Location:, 1987; published review (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Breasts, Bottles and Babies' Valerie Fildes
    - Les Grands sites naturels Author: Alison Jolly, 1988; published article (Box 6, Folder 5)
      (UNESCO World Heritage sites.) Le Courier, UNESCO, Aout 1998 5-11
    - F. Lanting, Le Saut perilleux des lemuriens GEO, 1980; magazine article (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Eight women in the Wild Author: Anne la Bastille Location:, 1980; magazine article (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Lemur Expedition Newsletter Author: A. Bishop, 1963; newsletter (Box 6, Folder 5)
      New York Zoological Society
    - Use of the Hand in Lower Primates Author: A. Bishop Location:, 1964; article (Box 6, Folder 5)
      reprinted from Evolutionary and Genetic Biology of primates vol. 2
    - Odd Animals of Madagascar Author: F. Lanting Location: Madagascar, May-88; magazine article (Box 6, Folder 5)
      portrait of 19 year old Bedo Jaosolo, National Geographic World 9-11. Published the year before Bedo was killed.
    - Control of the Hand in Lower Primates Author: A. Bishop Location:, Dec-62; reprinted article (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Lemur Eden Author: AJ Madagascar, 1984; magaine article (Box 6, Folder 5)
      BBC Wildlife June 1984, pp 303-308
    - A behavioural study of lemur in the field Author: A. Bishop Location:, 1962; grant proposal (Box 6, Folder 5)
      N and F proposal from the New York Zoological Society
    - Berenty Reserve tourist brochure Location: Berenty, 1980s; brochure (Box 6, Folder 5)
      WWF logo
    - We are the World' review Author: Alison Jolly, 1987; published review (Box 6, Folder 5)
      review of To Govern Evolution by Walter Truett Anderson, New Scientist p.73
    - day diaries Author: AJ, 1982-1999; day diaries (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - The wreck of the Torrey Canyon-epilogue Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1967; draft and letters (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Animal Kingdom 71: 41-13
    - review of Napier and Napier 'A Handbook of Living Primates' Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 1968; typed review (Box 6, Folder 5)
      one month after moving to Sussex
    - Maps (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
    - Daily Agendas (Box 6)
    - three notebooks Author: AJ Madagascar, small notebooks (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - De Heaulme Mandena Land (SAID) Location: Madagascar, 2011; map drawing (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Presentation to IAP Location: Madagscar, 2011; Itinerary (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Dobbin International Location: Madagascar, postcard (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Mission programme Location: Madagascar, 2011; Itinerary (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - A La Recherche des Tresors de la Grande ile: les Ressources Minerales Location: Madagascar, 2011; Report (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - A Political Economy Analysis of Governance in Madagascar Location: Madagascar, 2010; Report (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Azafady: rapport pour la region Anosy Location: Madagascar, Report (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Field notebooks Author: AJ Madagascar, small notebooks (Box 9)
    - Troop histories Location: Madagascar, 1990s; notes, reports and letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Girt and Splitear, Lemur catta
    - A - team Location: Madagascar, 1990s; notes, photos, reports and letters (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
      A troop, LC A troop history and mating data, Hantra and Doris, A team, Dubovick,
    - Infant Killing, Wounding and Predation in Eulemur and Lemur Author: M. Nakamichi Location: Madagascar, 1999; notes, reports and letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Infant killing 2nd Revision, Princeton, Bolton Institute, International Journal of Primatology
    - Cornsol Location: Madagascar, 1990s; notes, letters and reports (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Wendy Levash, Sue Caless, Princeton, Bolton Institute, Sonia C
    - Troop histories and range inertia of Lemur catta at Berenty, Madagascar: a 33 year perspective Author: AJ, Pride Madagascar, 1990s; notes, letters and reports (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Revised Ethan Range maps, Russell Tuttle, Princeton, International Journal of Primatology, Nakamichi and infants
    - Demography of Lemur Catta at Berenty Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1990s; paper and letter (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Russell Tuttle, International journal of primatology
    - Activity Budgets and Behavioral Thermoregulation in Eulemur fulvus rufus and lemur catta at Berenty Author: Theresa D. Williamson Location: Berenty, Madagascar, 1997; paper (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Williamson: Thermoregulation 1995
    - Variable use of territorial Behaviour in four troops of Eulemur fulvus rufus at Berenty Author: Hee-joo Park, Marisa Braun, Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, Madagascar, 1995; paper (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Spatial defense in lemur catta at different population densities in Berenty Author: AJ, Jon C. Cline, Marisa A. Braun, C. N. Mills, T.H. Dubovick, Hee-joo Park, C.B. Hicks Berenty, Madagascar, 1995; paper (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
      Territoriality: Braun and Park, Census meets 1994-95, Confrontation lists,
    - Earthwatch Location: Berenty, Madagascar, 1983; maps, graphs and notes (Box 10, Folder 4)
      First attempt to analyse whether LC troops influence each other at a distance
    - Territoriality paper Author: AJ, Kinnaird, O'Brien, Rasamimanana Location: Berenty, Madagscar, 1993; paper (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
      Princeton, figures and tables lemur catta territoriality,
    - Feeding similarity between lemur catta and Eulemur fulvus rufus in Berenty Reserve, Madagascar during the birth season Author: AJ, K.M. Heavers, S. Rasamoelina Location: Berenty, Madagascar, paper (Box 10, Folder 7)
      calculation tables
    - Travel Diary Author: AJ Uganda, Jun-06; notebook (Box 10, Folder 8)
      IPS Uganda primatology notes Bigodi swamp reserve: birds, grey-cheaked Mangabeys, Colobus Chimpanzee hunt in Kanyantale forest 1st chimps for me! Kibale red colobus. Richard Wrangham, Pat Wright, Kelly Stewart, Jan van Hoof, John Kasamene Makerere university with Patrick Mulundwe Kibale history.
    - Travel Diary Author: A J Gombe stream reserve, Tanzania, Jul-06; notebook (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Gombe stream with close encounter with Gremlin's family and lyrical evocation of Jane. Mahale Mountains reserve with close encounter with ex-alpha Fanana. Jane Goodall Institute as major local development agency. Arusha colobus with plumed tails. Brief list of Ako meetings Tana and bald lemurs with Wiebke Beng, Berenty.
    - Travel diary notes 1996 Author: Alison Jolly, Jun-05; notes (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Wenner Gren Sympsium on Gender and culture in primatology: Teresopolis, Brazi. Letter to RB and Margaretta about Donna Haraway, spoof summary of conference participants.
    - Madagascar Tradem Studies Location: Madagascar, 1985-1994; Documents (Box 10, Folder 9-18)
      Detailed listing of contents at the beginning of the box. Catherine Corson, scanned copies available
    - St Catherine's 1and11, World Bank Mission, Paz and Drough Location: Madagascar, 1984-1989, 1992; Documents (Box 11, Folder 1-9)
    - Madagascar Conservation Location: Madagascar, 1980s; Documents (Box 11, Folder 10-15)
    - Madagascar Conservation Location: Madagascar, 1980s; Documents (Box 12, Folder 1-7)
    - Berenty patch size paper, initiation of movement paper Location: Berenty, Madagascar, reports, letter and slides (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Initiation and leading of wild troop of lemur catta, troop size and patch use by lemur catta,Susan Pinkus, Rasamimanana, AJ,
    - AIBS lecture notes Location: Arlington, Virginia, 2002; notes and reports (Box 12, Folder 9)
      lecture in computor Impt notes on Joel Cracraft: allopatric speciation in New Guinea birds: this influenced my own lecture next day. Also impt because attended by Malagasy ambassador at a time of political turmoil. (and his family).
    - L C Symposium, "Constructing Lemur Catta" Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madison, Wisconsin, 1996; paper (Box 12, Folder 10)
      summary of viewpoints, IPS Madison, "Constructing Lemur Catta"
    - Old lectures, Sussex Author: Alison Jolly, 2002-2011; lecture notes (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Old Lectures, Lemur catta demography Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, lecture notes (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Old lectures, female dominance Author: Alison Jolly Location:, lecture notes (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Old lectures, Madagascar conservation Author: Alison Jolly Location:, lecture notes (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Old Lectures Author: AJ and RJ Winchester, 2006; lecture notes (Box 12, Folder 10)
      Can the lemurs save Madagascar?
    - Fordham summary lecture Author: Alison Jolly, 1996; lecture notes (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Philadelphia zoo video Location: Philadelphia, 1997; letters and notes (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Berenty grant proposals Location: Berenty, Madagascar, 2000s; letters, grant applications, (Box 12, Folder 11)
      CVs: Rasamimanana, Mertl-Millhollen, Blumenfeld-Jones, Wildlife Trust Grant: Storm Damage Effects on Lemur catta, Eulemur fulvus, and Forest Composition, Leverhulme Trust unsuccessful application for long term lemur ranging patterns, WCS unsuccessful application for long term lemur ranging patterns, Wenner Green application
    - Berenty tourism Location: Berenty, madagascar, 1989, 1999, 2000; Questionnaires and summary (Box 12, Folder 12)
      Quant summary in Sharon Katz' Princeton thesis
    - Berenty documents Location: Berenty, Madagascar, 1990s?; letters, reports, grant applications (Box 12, Folder 13)
      Grant proposals to National Geographic Society and Ney York Zool. Soc. for a survey of Lemur catta population across the south: to be done by Mark Pigeon, with Bob Sussman, Michael Pereira. Funded by NGS, but not carried out through Mark's ill health
    - Berenty 1972-3, Kathryn Dainis Blumenthal-Jones Location: Berenty, Madagascar, 1972-1973, 1983-1985; photo, maps, notes and thesis (Box 12, Folder 14)
      aerial photo Berenty 1950 from national survey, Blumenthal- Jones original 50 metre grid 1972-3, KDBJ tree map enlarged, KDBJ tree map enlarged, KD B-J original data, KDBJ day ranges, KDBJ methods, KDBJ lemur catta data, KDBJ October 1972 day ranges, KDBJ Oct-Dec 1972, Jan-Feb 1973 day ranges, KDBJ temperature data O'connor thesis 1983-85
    - Berenty trees: storm damage data Location: Berenty, Madagascar, 1998-99; letters, reports, data sample, photos, (Box 12, Folder 15)
      August 1998 photos from main gate to Picadilly showing lettet to Anne, Hanta, Kathy, Susan on Lemur news, tree and tables also on computor, tree data cattle drove never analysed, handwritten tree data, report to M. de heaulme on tree damage 1999, handwritten tree data sample, letter from Ethan Pride Oct 28 1999 on Berenty wind storm, letter from Kathryn Blumenthal-Jones Dec 1 1999 on assessing storm damage, storm damage data 1999,
    - Lera Miles thesis Location: Berenty, 1996; thesis (Box 12, Folder 16)
      Tamarind regeneration and distribution in Berenty reserve 1996, University College London
    - Berenty trees 2 Location: Berenty, Madgascar, original notebooks and papers (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Unpublished paper: Forest composition and storm damage at Berenty Reserve, Madagascar and comparison with Beza Mahafaly Reserve, A. Jolly, H. Rasamimanana, K. Blumenfeld-Jones, Ratovonirina. Also printout of Berenty Tree Data. Also field notebooks on trees
    - Flag trees and miscellaneous Location: Berenty, Madagascar, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Earthwatch 1992-93 trees on which lemur catta, propithecus verreauxi, eulemur fulvus concentrated feeding, three troops of each with overlapping ranges, flag trees 1991, flag trees 1993, cissus map for ankoba malaza, tree species codes, Susan pinkus veg. survey 1993 and card,
    - Berenty Miscellaneous Location: Berenty, Madagascar, 1990s; notes and reports (Box 13, Folder 3)
      includes de Heaulme report and Pluviometry. Also, Ichino, Mertl-Millhollen, Moret, Tahiry. George Williams,
    - Berenty notebooks Author: Alison Jolly, 2000?; small notebooks (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
    - Berenty Notebook October Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1989; notebook (Box 13, Folder 6)
      Territorial confrontations and walking banana sources
    - Berenty Notebook Oct? Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1990; notebook (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Berenty Notebook Sept. Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1991; notebook (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Berenty Notebook Oct? Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1992; notebook (Box 13, Folder 6)
      lemur census summaries, no troop descriptions
    - Berenty Notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1993; notebook (Box 13, Folder 7)
      lemurs, de Heaulme report, Earthwatch Giardia
    - Berenty Summary Notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1994; notebook (Box 13, Folder 7)
      lemurs, notes for Bali, CITES, Japan
    - Berenty lemur Notebook Sept-Oct Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1994; notebook (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Summaries of IDS from 1993. Takeover of Leonardo's troop by Girdletail (later called YB with Caffeine) lemurs.
    - Berenty Notebook Sept-Oct Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1995; notebook (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Lemurs. A quiet afternoon with A2 (andTracy Dubovick) Tails cut by Isabelle Porteus.
    - Berenty Notebook Sept-Oct Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1996; notebook (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Lemurs, Robert Drury notes
    - Berenty Notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1997; notebook (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Lemurs
    - Berenty Notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1998; notebook (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Berenty Notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1999; notebook (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Berenty Notebook Sept-Oct Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2000; notebook (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Lemurs and interviews with Jean and Aline de Heaulme for Lords and Lemurs.
    - Berenty Notebook Oct. Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2001; notebook (Box 13, Folder 9)
      only lemurs
    - Berenty Notebook Sept-Oct Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2002; notebook (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Lemurs, Mandrare Runoff, Williams GPS mapping
    - Berenty Notebook March Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2003; notebook (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Darting and measuring lemurs with vets Graham Crawford and Susan Ostapak, in an attempt to find cause of bald lemur syndrome. No success because 1. wrong season, 2. Leucaema hypothesis not yet thought of. Did find some lactating mothers in poor condition.
    - Berenty Notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2003; notebook (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Lemurs with Alison Tew. Dissection of 2 old females: one extreme leucaena affected, one not main difference brown hard small liver in Leucaena female. Peggy Motch notes on naturalistic troop Alexia Foulon picture.
    - Berenty Notebook Sept- Oct supplement Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 2003; notebook (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Initial queries re: Leucaena hypothesis
    - Berenty Notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2004; notebook (Box 13, Folder 11)
      lemurs, Lords and lemurs published, Philippe de Heaulme: Marchal, pre-colonial rubber exporter - Nampoana was his and Gallienis!
    - Berenty Notebook Sept-Oct Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2004; notebook (Box 13, Folder 11)
      tour with Jean de Heaulme, dissection of healthy female with broken neck - Georges MAP program, lemurs
    - Berenty Notebook Nov Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2004; notebook (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Berenty Notebook May Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2005; notebook (Box 13, Folder 13)
      lemurs only
    - Berenty Notebook Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2005; notebook (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Kily fruit failure, BBC team with Charlotte Wilinbrock, Mark Flowers, also Frederic Cebron and Emmanuelle Grundman- Josia, Debbie Custance
    - Berenty Notebook Sept-Oct Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 2006; notebook (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Lemurs, people: AJ, Hanta Rasamimanana, Anne Millhollen, Lisa Gould, Debbie Custance, Wiebke Berg. Tom and Anne Davidson, Graham and Susan Crawford, Haja Rambeloanivony, Kathryn and Donald Blumenfeld, Ichino, Soma, Nick, Matthieu, Airg, Nirina, Sahoby, Donald, Daniella, Stefano,Josia
    - Summary of Berenty Research Location: Berenty, 2006; typed report (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Report to de Heaulmes on Berenty Condition Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 2005; typed report (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Will Berenty Forest Survive? Location: Berenty, 2007; typed report (Box 13, Folder 12)
      Berenty giant outline 2007 for 2008-10, Josia Razafindrahanana, Anne Mertl-Millhollen, kathryn Blumenfeld-Jones